Sahil Johari

Pittsburgh PA 15219 | 214-458-7161 | sahiljohari12@gmail.com | LinkedIn | GitHub | Website

Summary of Qualifications

Offering 3 years of experience in engineering highly available, scalable, and real time applications. Currently working as a Front-end Software Engineer in a diverse team, building and improving user experience of exciting web apps using modern front-end frameworks.

Communication | Eye for design | Attention to Detail | Teamwork | Creativity | Customer Empathy | Curiosity

Skills

- HTML, CSS/SASS, JavaScript, React, Redux, Node, TypeScript, Cypress, Jest, Enzyme, Python, MySQL
- REST API, Git/GitHub, CI/CD, Responsive web design, UX, Content writing, Documentation

Professional Experience

Software Engineer - Rivers Agile - Pittsburgh, PA

FiCrowd

May 2020 - Present Provide high performance and scalable crowdfunding solutions by anticipating customer needs and building

- product features such as campaign creation and ability to donate funds to a campaign
- Design and architect user interaction with the application to enhance crowdfunding experience by continuously improving usability, accessibility, cross-browser compatibility, and performance of the product Streamline application development effort and code reusability by leveraging the strengths of front-end
- framework and organizing code into robust and maintainable UI components

<u>Technologies Used</u>: Angular 9, Bootstrap 4, CSS3, Node, AWS (Lambda, Cognito)

IBM Pittsburgh Lab August 2019 - May 2020

- Developed, using wireframes, fully functional front-end UI components for Discovery Tooling a user facing online tool in IBM Watson™ Discovery
- Contributed to the product vision by proposing and building a conversational feature (Chat Bot) using Discovery API to simplify the operational processes of customers
- Instituted new processes for writing integration tests by introducing Cypress framework into the stack to provide improved testability, maintainability, and code readability
- Successfully completed and deployed over 18 user stories/features for product release in November 2019
- Technologies Used: React, Redux, TypeScript, SASS, Node, Jest, Enzyme, Cypress

Senior Analyst - Capgemini Technology Services India Limited - India

Jetstar Airways Pty Ltd.

June 2015 – June 2017

- Reduced the lead time by 80% for the customer via generating and distributing over 125 reports by developing an automation web application using .NET framework
- Redesigned and implemented UI for a legacy application to offer improved aesthetics and user experience using jQuery and Bootstrap
- Technologies Used: HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap 3, ¡Query, ASP.NET, C#, Oracle PL-SQL

Education

Master of Science, Computer Science

Southern Methodist University, Dallas, Texas

Bachelor of Engineering, Information Technology

University of Mumbai, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India

GPA: 3.53/4.0 June 2015

May 2019

GPA: 70.13% (Final Year)

Additional Experience

Graduate Teaching Assistant

January 2019 - April 2019

Department of Computer Science and Engineering, Southern Methodist University - Dallas, Texas

- Course: Principles of Computer Science
- Instructed undergraduate students on hands-on programming sessions in Java conducted for a span of 8 weeks